Declared illegitimate aged 3. Tried for treason aged 21. Crowned Queen aged 25.
Elizabeth is a drama, history film directed by Shekhar Kapur.
The story of the ascension to the throne and the early reign of Queen Elizabeth the First, the endless attempts by
her council to marry her off, the Catholic hatred of her and her romance with Lord Robert Dudley.
Elizabeth I, played by Cate Blanchett.
Robert Dudley, Earl of Leicester, played by Joseph Fiennes.
Sir Francis Walsingham, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Duke of Norfolk, played by Christopher Eccleston.
The Pope, played by John Gielgud.
Sir William Cecil, played by Richard Attenborough.
Elizabeth is a 1998 British biographical historical drama film
directed by Shekhar Kapur and written by Michael Hirst.
It stars Cate Blanchett as Elizabeth I of England, with Geoffrey Rush, Christopher Eccleston,
Joseph Fiennes, John Gielgud, and Richard Attenborough in supporting roles.
The film is based on the early years of Elizabeth's reign, when she is elevated to the
throne after the death of her half-sister Mary I, who had imprisoned her.
As she establishes herself on the throne, she faces
plots and threats to take her down.
Elizabeth premiered at the 55th Venice International Film Festival on 8 September
1998 and was theatrically released in the United Kingdom on 23 October.
The film became a critical and commercial success.
Reviewers praised Kapur's direction, costume design, production values and most notably Blanchett's titular performance,
bringing her to international recognition, while the film grossed $82 million against its $30 million budget.
The film received three nominations at the 56th Golden Globe Awards, including for
the Best Motion Picture – Drama, with Blanchett winning Best Actress.
It received twelve nominations at the 52nd British Academy Film Awards, winning five
awards, including Outstanding British Film, and Best Actress (for Blanchett).
At the 71st Academy Awards, it received seven nominations, including for Best
Picture and Best Actress (for Blanchett), winning Best Makeup.
In 2007, Blanchett and Rush reprised their roles in Kapur's follow-up film
Elizabeth: The Golden Age, which covers the later part of Elizabeth's reign.
The film explores themes of queen, duke, treason, queen elizabeth i, tudor.
The tone is emotional.